Inventory of the Roger Mansell collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Prisoner-of-War Camps in Japan File, 1940-1947, 1978-2007 (Boxes 10-17, 36)
  - Fukuoka, 1942-1947, 1978-2004 (Boxes 10-11)
    - Camp 7-B (formerly no. 10), 1942, 2000s (Folder 11: 1)
      Includes sketch of camp, chart of deceased POWs, and miscellaneous reports. Photocopies.
    - Camp 10 (became no. 7-B), 1946 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Camp 14, 1947, 1986-2004 (Folder 11: 3-4)
    - Camp 17, 1945-1947, 1978-2004 (Folder 11: 5-9)
      One compact disc containing photographs.
    - Camp 18, undated (Folder 11: 10)
    - Camp 21, 22, and 23, 1945, 2003 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Camp 24 (Sendyu), 1945, 2003 (Folder 11: 12-14)
      One compact disc and one 3.5-inch floppy disk containing rosters.
    - Danielson, Dewey, 1945, 2003 (Folder 11: 15)
      Includes photocopies of letters home and diary.
    - Camp maps, 1945 (Folder 11: 16)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1946, 2001, undated (Folder 11: 17)
    - Reports on Fukuoka POW camps by John M. Gibbs, 1946 (Folder 11: 18)
    - Report on experience at Misheroda camp by M.D.S. Saunders, 1944-1945 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Hakodate, 1945-2006 (Boxes 11-12)
    - General, 2003-2005 (Folder 11: 20-21)
      Includes roster of deceased British internees and background research compiled by Wes Injerd.
    - Main camp, 1945-2006 (Folder 11: 22-23)
    - Sapporo camp, 1945, 2003-2006 (Folder 11: 24-25)
    - Camp 1, circa 1945 (Folder 11: 26)
    - Camp 2 (Akabira), circa 1945, undated (Folder 11: 27-29)
      Includes diary, aerial photograph of camp, and rosters.
    - Camp 3, 1945, 2003-2004 (Folder 11: 30)
    - Camp 4, 1945, 2003 (Folder 11: 31)
      One compact disc. Printed copy available in file.
    - Camp 6, early 2000s (Folder 11: 32)
      Includes notes and memoranda from interview with Pfc. Merle Swartz and one compact disc containing photographs.
    - Heer, Robert and Karen, 1943-1945, 2003-2006 (Folder 12: 1-2)
    - Zack, Milton E., 1945, undated (Folder 12: 3)
      Three compact discs containing memoir and photographs.
  - Hiroshima, 1942-1946, 2000-2006 (Boxes 12, 36)
    - Branch camp 1 (Zentsuji), 1942-2000 (Box-folder 12: 4-6, 36: 1)
      - Correspondence, photographs, and rosters, 1942-2000 (Folder 12: 4-5)
      - Schwartz, Jack, 1942-1945 (Folder 12: 6)
        Original notebook with signatures of officers at camp.
      - Schwartz, Jack, circa 1942 (Folder 36: 1)
        Original documents including instructions given to American Marines at Zentsuji by Major General Mizuhara on January 15, 1942, handwritten, and English translations of common Japanese phrases.
    - Branch camp 2 (Mitsui), undated (Folder 12: 7)
      Includes pencil sketch of camp.
    - Branch camps 4, 4-B, and 5-D, 1946, 2000s (Folder 12: 8)
    - Branch camp 9 (Ohana), 1945, 2005-2006 (Folder 12: 9-10)
      Includes photographs, maps, sketches, and rosters.
    - Baxter, John, 1995 (Folder 12: 11)
      Includes manuscript of self-published memoir titled "Not Much of a Picnic: Memoirs of a Conscript and Japanese Prisoner of War, 1941-1945."
  - Nagoya, 1942-1946, 2002-2003 (Box 12)
    - Funatsu camp, 2003 (Folder 12: 12)
      Includes sketch of camp and notes from interview with Ben D. Waldron.
    - Branch camp 1 (Kamioka), 2003 (Folder 12: 13)
    - Branch camp 1-B (Kamioka) (Folder 12: 14-16)
      - Makepeace, Ray, 2002 (Folder 12: 14)
      - Pase, Joseph G., 1942-1946 (Folder 12: 15)
      - Prospero, Nick, 1946, 2002 (Folder 12: 16)
    - Branch camp 5 or 7, circa 1945 (Folder 12: 17)
      Includes roster.
    - Branch camp 9, circa 1945, 2003 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Osaka, 1940-1970, 1993-2007 (Boxes 12-15)
    - Camp sketches, undated (Folder 12: 19)
      Includes sketches of Akenobe, Tsumori, Yodogawa, Oeyama, and Chikko.
    - Letter from Tama N. Nishokawa regarding airstrikes in Kobe, 1949 April (Folder 12: 20)
      Photocopy from Clarence W. Alvord collection at the University of Missouri, Western Historical Manuscript Collection.
    - List of men from Zentsuji to Ichioka, some Hirohata, 1942 (Folder 12: 21)
    - List of U.S. POWs, 1942 February 19 (Folder 12: 22)
      Photocopy of news clipping.
    - Photographs, notes, and testimonials, 1945-1950, 2000s (Folder 12: 23)
    - POW camp group, 1942-1945 (Folder 12: 24)
    - Report on executions at Osaka, 1945-1948 (Folder 12: 25)
    - Futatabi camp, 2000 (Folder 12: 26)
      Includes correspondence regarding Marc A. Schwartz.
    - Hirohata (Osaka Command), 1943-1946, 1997-2003 (Folder 12: 27-29)
      Includes photograph, reports and affidavits from the U.S. Office of War Crimes, and rosters.
    - Honshu camp, 1946 May (Folder 13: 1)
      List of POWs.
    - Ichioka Stadium Hospital, 1943-1945, 2000s (Folder 13: 2)
    - Kobe Hospital, 1945 (Folder 13: 3)
      One 3.5-inch floppy disk containing rosters. Printed copy available in folder.
    - Kobe House, 1945, 1999-2002 (Folder 13: 4-6)
    - Rokuroshi, 1943-1947, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 13: 7-11)
      - Correspondence, 1947, 2001-2002 (Folder 13: 7)
      - Identification cards, 1945 (Folder 13: 8)
      - Photographs of rescue, 1945 (Folder 13: 9)
        Photocopies. One compact disc containing scans of photographs from the National Archives.
      - Reports, affidavits, and diary of Andrew Atholl Duncan, 1943-1945 (Folder 13: 10)
      - Rosters, circa 1945, 2000s (Folder 13: 11)
        Includes some rosters of POWs at Zentsuji.
    - Tsuruga and Tanagawa camps, 1942-1945, 2003 (Folder 13: 12)
    - Umeda camp, circa 1942-1946, 2000s (Folder 13: 13-14)
    - Camp 1 (Main Camp/Chikko), 1946 (Folder 13: 15-16)
    - Camp 3 (Yodogawa), 1942-1946 (Folder 13: 17)
      Includes the diary of Bill Reardon and photocopies of affidavits from U.S. Office of War Crimes.
    - Camp 3 (Yodogawa), 1945, 2004 (Folder 14: 1-3)
      Includes news clippings and rosters.
    - Camp 3-B (Oeyama), undated (Folder 14: 4)
      Includes list of Japanese guards.
    - Camp 4-B (Ikuno), circa 1945, 2006 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Camp 4-D (Sakurajima), 1945, 2000s (Folder 14: 6)
    - Camp 5 (Kawasaki), 2002 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Camp 5-B (Tsuruga), undated (Folder 14: 8)
    - Camps 6 and 26 (Tsuruga), undated (Folder 14: 9)
    - Camp 7 (Toyama City), 1943 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Camp 7-B (Takefu), circa 1945, 2006 (Folder 14: 11)
    - Camp 10 (Maibara), 1945, 2000s (Folder 14: 12)
      One 3.5-inch floppy disk containing rosters of deceased POWs. Printed copy available in folder.
    - Camp 12-B (Hirohata), 1994 (Folder 14: 13)
    - Camp 13-B (Tsumori), 1945, 2006 (Folder 14: 14)
    - Camp 15 (Oeyama), 1945 (Folder 14: 15)
    - Camp 18-B (Wakinohama), 2003 (Folder 14: 16)
    - Camp 22, undated (Folder 14: 17)
    - Charles, Myron W., 1940-1944 (Folder 14: 18)
      Includes scans of photographs and clippings.
    - Cobb, Charles A., 1992-2003 (Folder 14: 19)
    - Dalzell, James W., 2002 (Folder 14: 20)
    - Kidd, John F., 2000 (Folder 14: 21)
    - Lane, John, circa 1943, 1992 (Folder 14: 22-23)
      Includes photocopy of diary from Changi camp in Singapore and clippings. Also includes one zip disk and one 3.5-inch floppy disk.
    - Locke, A. J., 2001 (Folder 14: 24)
    - Kramerich, Stephen, 2001 (Folder 14: 25)
      Includes manuscript of memoir and notes from interview with Mansell.
    - Marshall, Peter, 2002 (Folder 14: 26)
      One compact disc containing photographs and transcript and notes from interview.
    - Meyers, A. W., 2001 (Folder 15: 1)
    - Nichols, Frank, 2003 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Nixon, Tom, 1942-1943, 1970, undated (Folder 15: 3)
    - Plummer, Nathan, 2001-2002 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Rand, James L., 1945, 2000 (Folder 15: 5)
    - Raymond, Stephan, 1946, 2000-2002 (Folder 15: 6)
      Two 3.5-inch floppy disks and one compact disc containing photographs and Raymond's memoir.
    - Reynolds, Victor C., circa 1945-1946, 1991 (Folder 15: 7)
      Includes memoir, rosters, and photocopies of aerial photographs.
    - Schwartz, Jack W., undated (Folder 15: 8)
    - Settles, Edward W., 2000 (Folder 15: 9)
    - Shane, George, 2000 (Folder 15: 10)
    - Tarnowski, Zemo, 2001 (Folder 15: 11)
    - Taylor, Jack, 1940s, 2002 (Folder 15: 12)
      Civilian internee at Futatabi.
    - Thomas, Kim, 1945, 1993 (Folder 15: 13)
      Assistant Manager Pan Am, Guam.
  - Sendai, 1943-1945, 1987-2007 (Boxes 15-16)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2002 (Folder 15: 14)
    - Film of Sendai rescue, 1945 (Folder 15: 15)
      One DVD.
    - Aoumi camp, circa 1945 (Folder 15: 16)
    - Camp 1 (Yumoto), undated (Folder 15: 17)
    - Camp 2 (Furukawa), 1945, 1987-2003 (Folder 15: 18-21)
      - Correspondence with Geoffrey Monument, 1987-2005 (Folder 15: 18)
      - Personal narratives, 1945-1993 (Folder 15: 19)
      - Photographs, flyers, and email correspondence, 1945, 2003 (Folder 15: 20)
      - Roster of British internees, circa 1945 (Folder 15: 21)
        Photocopied from National Archives of Australia.
    - Camp 3 (Hosukura), circa 1945, 2004 (Folder 16: 1)
      One 3.5-inch floppy disk containing rosters and sketch of camp. Printed copy available in folder.
    - Camp 4-B (Ohasi), 1943-1945 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Camp 5 (Kamaishi), circa 2007 (Folder 16: 3-4)
      Includes memoirs of Robert Foster and Richard T. Winter, related correspondence, and rosters. Also includes one compact disc.
    - Camp 6 (Shiragawa), 1945, 2004 (Folder 16: 5-6)
      One compact disc containing rosters.
    - Camp 8 (Kosaka Mine), circa 1945 (Folder 16: 7)
    - Camp 9, 1946 April 18 (Folder 16: 8)
      Includes photocopy of report on investigation by Supreme Commander for Allied Powers.
  - Tokyo, 1942-1954, 1995-2005, undated (Boxes 16-17)
    - General, 1942-2006 (Folder 16: 9-12)
      Includes reports on the transfer of POWs, clippings on Tokyo Rose, aerial photographs of Honshu camp, sketch of Ashio camp, and photograph of Shinagawa hospital. Photocopies.
    - Miscellaneous research on Tokyo camps, 1945-1946, 2000 (Folder 16: 13)
    - Yokohama Cemetery records, 2002-2003 (Folder 16: 14)
    - Bunka camp, 1946 (Folder 16: 15)
    - Omori camp, 1945, 2002 (Folder 16: 16)
    - Camp 1-B (Kawasaki), circa 1945, 2000s (Folder 16: 17)
    - Camp 1-D (Yokohama), undated (Folder 16: 18)
      Formerly known as Tokyo Camp no. 2.
    - Camp 2 and 2-B (Kawasaki), 1942-2003 (Folder 16: 19-20)
    - Camp 3-B (Yokohama), 1945-1946 (Folder 16: 21)
      Also known as Stadium Camp.
    - Camp 4-B (Naoetsu), 2005 (Folder 16: 22)
    - Camp 5 and 5-B, Branch (Niigata), 1945, 1995 (Folder 16: 23-24)
    - Dispatch camp 5 (Kawasaki), 1943-1945 (Folder 16: 25)
    - Camp 7-D (Omi), 1945, 2003 (Folder 17: 1)
      Includes program from performance at Aomi Hall and rosters. Also includes one 3.5-inch floppy disk.
    - Camp 8-B (Hitachi), 1944 (Folder 17: 2)
    - Camp 10-D (Yokohama/Tsurumi), 1944-1954 (Folder 17: 3)
      Includes records relating to Orville Stanford.
    - Camp 12 (Mitsushima), 1944, 2002 (Folder 17: 4-5)
      One 3.5-inch floppy disk and one compact disc containing rosters.
    - Camp 18-D (Yokohama), undated (Folder 17: 6)
    - Camp 21-D (Nomachi), 1985, 2004 (Folder 17: 7)
    - Carney, Frank J., 1942-1944 (Folder 17: 8)
      Includes one CD sound disc of Radio Tokyo broadcasts.
    - Johnson, John K., 2004 (Folder 17: 9)
    - Mayhue, L. F., circa 1944 (Folder 17: 10)
    - Mosher, Alfred, 2000-2001 (Folder 17: 11)
    - Raymond, Robert L, undated (Folder 17: 12-14)
      Includes manuscript of memoir.
    - Sabo, Andrew, 1942-1945, 2005 (Folder 17: 15)
- Prisoner-of-War Camps Outside Japan File, 1936-1949, 1965-2007 (Boxes 17-25)
  Consists of rosters, camp sketches, notes, email correspondence, diaries, memoirs, and photocopies of archival materials. Arranged by geographical location, then alphabetically by subject or format, as defined by Mansell. Files relating to individual internees are listed alphabetically at the end of each subseries.
  - China, 1941-1945, 1983-2005 (Folder 17: 16-20)
    - 14th attacks on Kowloon Docks and article from Japan Times, 1944, 2005 (Folder 17: 16)
    - China gunboats, 1999, undated (Folder 17: 17)
    - Hong Kong, 1992-2005, undated (Folder 17: 18)
      Personal narrative of Vince Calder and POW flow chart.
    - Shanghai, Ash Camp, 1941-1945, 2003 (Folder 17: 19)
    - Shanghai Bridge House, 1983, 2002 (Folder 17: 20)
  - Formosa (Taiwan), 1942-1948, 1997-2005 (Box 18)
    - Karenko camp, undated (Folder 18: 1)
    - Toroku camp, 1944, 2005 (Folder 18: 2)
      Includes partial rosters of Hokusen Maru and related correspondence.
    - Ink sketch of Karentio, Tamsata, and steam ship, undated (Folder 18: 3)
    - Kinkaseki POW Memorial, 1999-2000 (Folder 18: 4)
      Includes related correspondence.
    - Kinkaseki War Crimes, circa 1945 (Folder 18: 5)
      Affidavit of Major Gross.
    - Reports, 1942-1945 (Folder 18: 6-10)
      - Background reports on camps by the Red Cross and other agencies, 1942-1945 (Folder 18: 6-7)
      - POWs in Formosa, 1944 (Folder 18: 8)
      - "Exhibit J," orders to flee, 1945 (Folder 18: 9)
      - "Exhibit O," orders to kill, 1945 (Folder 18: 10)
    - Rescued POWs aboard U.S. ship, 1945 September (Folder 18: 11)
      One compact disc of photographs and some printed copies.
    - Research on individuals, 1948, 2001-2004 (Folder 18: 12-13)
    - Edwards, Jack, 1997-2001 (Folder 18: 14)
    - Heer, Robert, 2005 (Folder 18: 15)
    - Willner, Stanley, 1999 (Folder 18: 16)
    - Worthington, Josiah Winstar, 1943-1946, undated (Folder 18: 17-20)
      Includes printed copies of diary.
  - Korea, 2002 (Folder 19: 1)
    "Prisoners on Parade: Japan Party 'B,'" Fran de Goer and Helen Masterman-Smith, article.
  - Manchuria, 1941-1945, 1980s-2003 (Folder 19: 2-12)
    - General, 1945, 2003 (Folder 19: 2)
      Operation orders, clipping, and correspondence. Includes a list of deceased POWs from Mukden camps.
    - Danielson, Dewey, 1941-1945 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Herbst, Mark G., 1945 (Folder 19: 4)
    - Johler, Jacob, undated (Folder 19: 5-8)
      Includes photocopy of diary and photocopies of clippings and reports. Also includes three DVDs containing slideshows of photographs.
    - Krebs, John, 1996-2001 (Folder 19: 9)
    - Page, Harold Lloyd, 1980s (Folder 19: 10-11)
      Includes personal narrative and copies of photographs from visit to POW camp site.
    - Quinn, Michael A., 1947, undated (Folder 19: 12)
  - Mariana Islands (Guam), 1936-1965, 1991-2005 (Boxes 19-20)
    - China Clipper, logs and statistics, 1965 (Folder 19: 13)
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Folder 19: 14-15)
    - Diaries, undated (Folder 19: 16)
    - Interview notes and memoranda, 2000-2005 (Folder 19: 17)
    - Japanese political and military reports, 1941-1952 (Folder 19: 18)
    - McMillan report on the surrender of Guam and rosters of convicted defendants, 1941-1945, 1999 (Folder 19: 19-20)
    - Notes from interviews with POWs and readings on Zentsuji and Guam, circa 2000-2005 (Folder 20: 1-3)
    - Photographs of Guam, Pan Am collection at University of Miami, 1940s (Folder 20: 4)
    - Photographs of POWs, 1944 (Folder 20: 5)
    - Printed matter and clippings, 1936, 2004 (Folder 20: 6)
    - Rosters of missing personnel, 1941-1949 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Bacon, William, 1945, 2002 (Folder 20: 8)
      One compact disc of photographs. Thumbnails of images printed out.
    - Oppenborn, Fred, 2000-2002 (Folder 20: 9)
    - Ploke, John, undated (Folder 20: 10)
    - Thomas, Jim, 1995 (Folder 20: 11)
    - Wells, Grant, 1991-2000 (Folder 20: 12)
      Pan Am mechanic.
    - Wolfsheimer, Frank, 1941, 2000-2005 (Folder 20: 13)
      One DVD film of planes landing at Guam, 26 minutes.
  - Netherlands East Indies (NEI), 1942-1946, 1999-2003 (Boxes 20-21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2001, undated (Folder 20: 14)
    - Correspondence of Captain James L. Norwood, 1946 May (Folder 20: 15)
    - Diary of Tom Pledger, 1945, 1999-2002 (Folder 20: 16)
      Includes related correspondence, photograph, and map of Hainan.
    - Dutch reports on Japanese POW camps in East Asia, 2000-2003 (Folder 20: 17-18)
    - Interview notes, undated (Folder 20: 19)
    - List of POWs from Australian War Museum, undated (Folder 20: 20)
    - Maps of POW camps, undated (Folder 20: 21)
    - Report on Makassar prison camp, Coggins papers, 1945-1946 (Folder 20: 22)
    - Researching Record Group 189 at the National Archives, 2003 (Folder 20: 23)
    - Richards, Rees, undated (Folder 21: 1)
      Transcripts from notebooks.
    - Rohletter, James Barry, 2001 (Folder 21: 2)
    - Java, 1942, 1999-2002, undated (Folder 21: 3-14)
      - Airfields, research notes, undated (Folder 21: 3)
      - Battles, 1942 February-March (Folder 21: 4)
        Includes research on the Battle of Makassar Strait, Badung Strait, Sunda Strait, and Java Sea.
      - "Loss of U.S.S. Pillsbury," Russell B. Bradford, Sea Classics magazine, 2002 February (Folder 21: 5)
      - HMAS Perth, 1999 (Folder 21: 6)
      - U.S.S. Houston reunion, 1999 (Folder 21: 7)
        Includes photographs.
      - U.S.S. Houston (CA-30) reunion, 1999-2001 (Folder 21: 8-10)
        Includes newsletters, photographs, correspondence, and notes.
      - Bergman, Albert, 1999 (Folder 21: 11)
      - Laybe, Guthrie Fitzhugh, 1999 (Folder 21: 12)
      - MacIntosh, Jim, 2000-2001 (Folder 21: 13-14)
        Includes correspondence between Mansell and Joan MacIntosh and enclosed clippings. Also includes one zip disk.
    - New Guinea, research on Yoshichika Tokugawa, 2006 (Folder 21: 15)
    - Sumatra, circa 1946, 1999-2000 (Folder 21: 16-18)
      - Correspondence with George Duffy, 1999-2000 (Folder 21: 16)
      - Map of Malaysia, undated (Folder 21: 17)
      - Report on prison and railway construction by Stanley E. Gorski, circa 1946 (Folder 21: 18)
  - Philippines, 1941-1948, 1970-2007 (Boxes 22-24)
    - General (Folder 22: 1-10)
      - Correspondence and news clipping, 2002-2005, undated (Folder 22: 1)
      - Government reports on POW camps, 1944-1945 (Folder 22: 2)
      - MacArthur's list of deceased Air Corps officers, 1941 (Folder 22: 3)
      - Notes, undated (Folder 22: 4)
      - Pasay POW Camp, 2002, undated (Folder 22: 5)
      - Places of Divine Worship, Far East Air Forces, United States Air Force, 1940s (Folder 22: 6)
      - Report on POWs, 1944 September (Folder 22: 7)
      - Grimes, Ken, 1998-1999 (Folder 22: 8)
      - Mora, George, 1999 (Folder 22: 9)
      - Sams, Gerald and Margaret, 1999 (Folder 22: 10)
    - Bataan (Folder 22: 11-20)
      - Articles, clippings, and other writings, 1999-2007 (Folder 22: 11-12)
        Includes excerpts of Charles Johnstone, "Bataan Death March"; David Knox, "Death March: The Survivors of Bataan"; Kai Martin, "That There Will Be War No More"; Alexander Wolff, "Tonelli's Run"; and Stephen Melillo, "That We Might Live."
      - Permissions to quote, 2000 (Folder 22: 13)
      - Roster of deceased at general hospital, undated (Folder 22: 14)
      - Cobb, George, 1999 (Folder 22: 15)
      - Commander, Richard, 1991-1995, undated (Folder 22: 16)
      - Mazer, Maurice, 1999 (Folder 22: 17)
      - Munson, Gerald, 1941-1945, 2004 (Folder 22: 18)
      - Thomas, Arthur B. "Bud,", 2000 (Folder 22: 19)
      - Vernon, John Florimond, 1945 (Folder 22: 20)
    - Bilibid (Folder 22: 21-22)
      - Diary of Richard T. Tirk, 1943-1945 (Folder 22: 21)
      - Research on individuals, 1944-1945, 2003 (Folder 22: 22)
    - Cabanatuan (Boxes 22-23)
      - Notes, undated (Folder 22: 23)
      - Rosters of personnel rescued in raid, 1941-1945, 2006-2007 (Folder 22: 24-25)
      - Cowan, James H., 1970, 2002 (Folder 23: 1-2)
        Includes manuscript titled "Bataan: A Survivor's Memoir" and related correspondence. See also Box 2 for earlier version.
      - Lewis, John, 2003 (Folder 23: 3)
        Interview notes.
    - Camp O'Donnell, 1999 (Folder 23: 4)
      Scope and COntents note
      Correspondence and clipping.
    - Corregidor, 1942, 1999-2005 (Folder 23: 5-6)
      Rosters, bibliographies, and photocopy of photograph.
    - Los Baños, 1945, undated (Folder 23: 7-10)
      Includes photocopies of photographs of rescue, research on individuals, maps, and three DVDs containing film footage of interviews with civilian and enlisted internees.
    - Malaybay, 1941-1943 (Folder 23: 11)
      Includes one compact disc containing photographs of POW Abraham Sabbatini.
    - Manila (Folder 23: 12-18)
      - Clarke Air Base, history of, undated (Folder 23: 12)
      - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Folder 23: 13)
      - Leyte Shimbun supplement, undated (Folder 23: 14)
      - List of internees at Baguio, undated (Folder 23: 15)
      - Manila Bulletin clipping, 1941 December 26 (Folder 23: 16)
      - Sakakida, Richard, undated (Folder 23: 17)
      - Utinskey, Margaret, 1948 (Folder 23: 18)
    - Palawan (Boxes 23-24)
      - American Guerrillas of Mindandao (AGOM), 1942-2005 (Folder 23: 19)
      - Palawan Massacre, 1942-1944, 1999 (Folder 23: 20-21)
      - Puerto Princessa death list, 1944 December (Folder 23: 22)
      - Elliott, Bruce G., undated (Folder 24: 1-2)
        Includes interview notes, correspondence, photocopies of photographs, and memoir of Walter Wallace.
  - Southeast Asia, 1941-1946, 1985-2002 (Box 24)
    - General, 1941-1946, 1985-2002 (Box-folder 24: 3-7)
      - Records of 2nd Battalion, the Gordon Highlanders, 1941-1945 (Folder 24: 3)
      - Research on Rangoon and Burma camps, 1946, 2000s (Folder 24: 4)
      - Roster of POWs in Rangoon, undated (Folder 24: 5)
      - Boatman, Harvey W., 1987-1991 (Folder 24: 6)
      - Smith, "Yasme Nei,", 1999 (Folder 24: 7)
        Correspondence.
    - Borneo, 1999-2005 (Folder 24: 8)
    - Death Railway (Folder 24: 9-11)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and maps, 1999 (Folder 24: 9)
      - S.S. Pampanito, 1999 (Folder 24: 10)
      - Watson, Charles, 1996-2000 (Folder 24: 11)
        "Tears of Gratitude," memoir and related correspondence.
    - Malaya, circa 1946 (Folder 24: 12)
      Rosters of deceased, Kuala Lumpur.
    - Singapore (Box-folder 24: 13-27)
      - Australian Imperial Forces (AIF), 1999 (Folder 24: 13)
      - Changi camp roster and map, 2003 (Folder 24: 14)
      - Royal New Zealand Air Force (RNZAF), 1945, 2000 (Folder 24: 15)
      - Baker, Guy T., 1999 (Folder 24: 16)
      - Berwick, Clyde, 1999 (Folder 24: 17)
      - Carter, Dennis "Nick,", 1999 (Folder 24: 18)
      - Clarke, A. G., 2001 (Folder 24: 19)
      - Clifford, 1999 (Folder 24: 20)
      - Iannarelli, Anthony, 1999 (Folder 24: 21)
      - Kelly, Terence, 1999 (Folder 24: 22)
      - Lane, John, 1940s, 1985-1999 (Folder 24: 23)
      - Mansell, Frank, 2000-2002 (Folder 24: 24)
      - McCarty, Frank, 1999-2000 (Folder 24: 25)
      - Partridge, Frank J., 2001 (Folder 24: 26)
        Royal Army Medical Corps.
      - Woolard, Walter, circa 1945, 1999-2000 (Folder 24: 27)
  - Wake Island, 1942-1946, 1990s-2005 (Folder 25: 1-12)
    - General, 1942-1946, 2002-2005 (Folder 25: 1-2)
      Correspondence, rosters, and clippings.
    - Civilian POWs, 1941-2004 (Folder 25: 3-5)
      Correspondence, rosters, and personal narratives.
    - Wake Island Defenders Reunion, 2005 October (Folder 25: 6)
      Brochure and one DVD containing a slideshow of photographs from the reunion.
    - Dodge, Bernard, undated (Folder 25: 7)
    - Herron, Merle, undated (Folder 25: 8)
    - Mitsumasa, Watanabe, 1944-1945, 2002 (Folder 25: 9)
      Diary excerpts.
    - O'Guinn, Allan Asbury, 1940s, 1990s (Folder 25: 10-11)
      Includes memoir and one compact disc.
    - Wilcox, Lee Wilson, 1942-1943 (Folder 25: 12)
- Civilian Prisoner-of-War Camps File, 1939-2010 (Boxes 25-27, 36-37)